<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                         "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="TODO">
<title>Planned features</title>
<subtitle>A very rough roadmap of ADG features implementation</subtitle>

<para>The following list is roughly in implementation order. All the improvements
must be reflected in the demo programs, where applicable.</para>

<simplesect id="TODO.0.4.0">
<title>Road to adg-0.4.0</title>

<itemizedlist mark="circle">
   <listitem override="disc">Split mathematic stuff in its own library. It will be called CPML,
   that is Cairo Path Manipulation Library.</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">Avoid wrapping of cairo APIs in AdgPath.</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">Implement AdgToyText, a basic text entity using the cairo "toy" text API.</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">Implement AdgTranslatable, a shared interface for entities that
   can be translated.</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">Implement AdgRotable, a shared interface for entities that can be rotated.</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</simplesect>

<simplesect id="TODO.0.5.0">
<title>Road to adg-0.5.0</title>

<itemizedlist mark="circle">
   <listitem override="disc">Provide CPML APIs for accessing cairo paths and browse their segments
   (a contiguous line segment).</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">Provide CPML APIs for accessing segments and browse their primitives
   (a single line / curve / close path).</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">CPML APIs to offset cairo paths: specifically, a decent
   approximation for single Bézier curves must be implemented.</listitem>
   <listitem>Provide basic CPML APIs to find intersection between cairo paths.</listitem>
   <listitem override="disc">Generate documentation for CPML.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add a fillet operation.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add a chamfer operation.</listitem>
   <listitem>Move AdgTranslatable and AdgRotable directly inside AdgEntity.</listitem>
   <listitem>Change building scripts to get the Gtk+ dependency optional.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add AdgLayout, a GtkLayout derived class that could accept an AdgCanvas.</listitem>
   <listitem>Optimize the implemented entities applying the 0.3 ADG infractrusture
   and enable caching where applicable.</listitem>
   <listitem>Use AdgToyText to draw dimenstion quote where applicable.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add a "beyond" property to AdgDimStyle to be used when extending the
   baseline beyond the extension lines. If not specified, it must default to
   3 x arrow size.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add a three-state enum to adg-enums.h: ADG_THREE_STATE_OFF,
   ADG_THREE_STATE_ON and ADG_THREE_STATE_DEFAULT.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add the three-state "outside" property to allow forcing an outside quote.
   In the default state, the outside must be decided by the space between
   the extension lines: if greather than 3 x arrow size => inside arrows.</listitem>
   <listitem>Implement the outside arrows in AdgLDim.</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</simplesect>

<simplesect id="TODO.0.6.0">
<title>Road to adg-0.6.0</title>

<itemizedlist mark="circle">
   <listitem>Rename Arrow to Marker: the latter is more generic (that is, better).</listitem>
   <listitem>Rename StyleId to StyleType: the latter is more clear.</listitem>
   <listitem>Implement AdgMarker as a customizable entity able to render (at least)
   the styles defined in AdgMarkerStyleType. Also, the ARROW and TRIANGLE
   styles should follow the director path that could be a curve. Use the
   METAPOST solution suggested by John Hobby I don't know where, that is,
   given <parameter>angle</parameter> and <parameter>size</parameter>, rotate the path by half <parameter>angle</parameter> in both directions,
   look for intersection with a circle at the end of the director path
   with radius <parameter>size</parameter>, close the resulting path and fill the arrow.</listitem>
   <listitem>Rework styles by using GObject and properties.</listitem>
   <listitem>Modify AdgMarkerStyle to use the newly implemented AdgMarker entity.</listitem>
   <listitem>Implement a basic AdgXatchStyle, derived from AdgLineStyle.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add AdgADim, the angular dimension.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add AdgRDim, the radial dimension.</listitem>
   <listitem>AdgPath should be an abstract class from which derive AdgPolyline,
   the basic stroked path entity.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add AdgXatch deriving AdgPath.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add AdgToyTable, a container for AdgToyText in a framed environment.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add AdgTitleBlock, a complex entity in paper space used to frame the
   sheet and show the general drawing data (title, scale, date and so on).</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</simplesect>

<simplesect id="TODO.unknown">
<title>Road to unknown</title>

<itemizedlist mark="circle">
   <listitem>Implement AdgModel and the model-view interaction.</listitem>
   <listitem>Implement AdgText, a generic text management, using pango.</listitem>
   <listitem>Add self-intersection API for CPML segments.</listitem>
   <listitem>Implement shape tolerances.</listitem>
   <listitem>Improve Bézier offset approximation enabling the choice of approximate
   a single curve with multiple offset curves.</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</simplesect>

</chapter>
